Erick Ronald German Mamani Aguilar Business Intelligence Analyst

khorneflakesdev@gmail.com

Phone. +591 69839682

Murillo, La Paz - Bolivia.

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>GitHub</u>

I am a professional with experience in the commercial sector and skills in data management. My initial exposure to data was through the use of CRM software for decision-making and business strategy planning. I am interested in further developing my skills in programming and data analysis, and I have acquired knowledge in Python, SQL, GCP, AWS, and data visualization tools such as Dash, Plotly, Power BI.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

Python, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Excel, Google Cloud SQL, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3), Dash & Plotly, API management, FastAPI, Javascript, Svelte, Git, Figma and Linux

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst May 2023 - Present

Multicompras Qn., Ltda Santa Cruz, Bolivia.

- Task automation using Python.
- Implementation of an ETL process to collect data from various sources (CRMs) for a centralized and normalized database on AWS.
- Establishment of an API to provide reports.
- Collaboration with management, sales, and inventory teams for the creation of reports based on their needs.
- Creation of Power BI dashboards to monitor sales, coverage, and pre-sales across different branches.
- Development of a WhatsApp chatbot to measure customer interactions and identify common questions and issues.

Commercial Analyst

May 2020 - Mar 2022

Inox Supply Ingenieria, La Paz, Bolivia.

- Use of data analysis tools to identify trends and patterns in customer behavior and inventory.
- Preparation of data analysis reports for customers and inventory using pivot tables and charts.
- Communication with the marketing team to coordinate the implementation of action plans.

Audit Assistant Aug 2018 - Feb 2020

Gobierno Autónomo Municipal de La Paz, La Paz, Bolivia.

- Work in the Control of Works department of the La Paz municipality in collaboration with legal and architectural teams.
- Monitoring, analysis, and evaluation of public works contracts.
- Measurement of compliance with established deadlines and budgets in contracts, and assessment of community satisfaction with completed projects.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- Data Science, Henry Bootcamp, 2022.
- Last year of Financial Auditing (on hold), Universidad NUR, 2020 2023.
- Higher Technical Degree in Accounting, Instituto Tecnico de Educacion Bancaria, 2015 2018.

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate SFPC, 2022.
- Scientific Computing with Python, FreeCodeCamp, 2022.
- Data Analysis with Python, FreeCodeCamp, 2022.
- Business Analysis for Data Science Course, Platzi, 2021.

LANGUAGES

- English B2 - Intermediate.